Amanda Erakovic



(902) 526-0894



aerakovic@gmail.com



Nova Scotia

SKILLS

- Microsoft Azure Administration
- SQL
- SSIS
- Azure Data Factory
- Power BI

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Azure Consultant

Progressive Pandas July 2022 - Present

Application Administrator

WCG Services February 2016 - July 2022

Technical Analyst

Reliable Controls

December 2014 - February 2016

Technical Analyst (Co-op) *Maximus Canada*

July 2014 - December 2014

EDUCATION

Computer Network Electronics Technician Certificate

Camosun College 2013 - 2014

ABOUT ME

I am an IT professional with almost 10 years of experience supporting hybrid IT infrastructure and Microsoft Azure cloud solutions. I possess strong analytical, troubleshooting, problem-solving, and excellent communication skills. I am committed to continuous learning, professional development, and personal improvement. I am currently taking online courses to learn advanced data engineering and analytics skills with the goal of becoming a professional data engineer.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Over the course of my career, I have provided support for a wide range of Azure services, enterprise applications, and infrastructure. I worked closely with clients, stakeholders, and internal staff to evaluate, implement, manage, and support hybrid and cloud environments.

Database Administration:

- Provided reliable access to datasets for the purpose of Power BI reports by configuring and deploying SSIS packages and monitoring data transfers from production to reporting servers using Azure Data Factory.
- Assisted in the design, creation, and maintenance of MS-SQL databases by writing queries, views, and stored procedures in production, test, and development environments.
- Configured, implemented, administered, and monitored Power BI, SQL (on-prem and in Azure), and Azure Data Factory.

Project Contributions:

- Evaluated business requirements, recognized possibilities to enhance business services, identified opportunities to reduce operational costs, developed, and implemented technical and business solutions.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to gather requirements, understand business needs, design solutions, and plan implementation accordingly.
- Provided technical expertise in a broad range of infrastructure technologies and new systems to managers, directors, and other senior staff on strategic direction for business information technology, and technology policies, procedures, and standards.
- Configured and provided support for Azure services and Microsoft 365 products and services.
- Handled multiple competing priorities and met deadlines reliably.

Administration:

- Supported Tier 2 technicians by developing user manuals that provided business rules and problem resolution procedures, guidance, and training.
- Maintained and developed functionality of incident tracking tools to meet business requirements for multiple departments.
- Drafted and maintained training, administration and security documentation.

Troubleshooting:

- Exercised strong analytical and problem-solving abilities using a logical, systematic, sequential approach with a strong attention to detail.
- Acted as a point of escalation for Tier 2 technicians and resolved complex issues.
- Effectively communicated technical problems, processes, and solutions to peers and stakeholders.
- Conducted problem identification, investigation, and resolution with the use of diagnostic hardware and software; addressed issues and implemented solutions to prevent future occurrences.
- Participated in problem review meetings to determine appropriate actions and provided updates.

Interpersonal:

- Displayed strong oral and written communication skills.
- Demonstrated excellent active listening skills; effectively comprehending, clarifying, summarizing, and reiterating information.
- Adapted to learn new ideas, principles, procedures, and concepts in dynamic and rapidly changing environments.
- Established priorities, determined available resources, and assigned work to self, peers, and others.
- Established and maintained effective professional working relationships with a variety of internal and external contacts.
- Trained, coached, and mentored Tier 2 technicians to meet job expectations, understand policy changes, and use equipment properly.